<?xml version="1.0"?>
<dungeon dgnname="The Rumor Mill">
	<intro>
		You step inside the door beneath the old weather-beaten sign: The Rumor Mill,
        and find yourself in the interior of a darkened and smokey room.
        Serving women are delivering food to the patrons at the various tables scattered about.
        The clatter of crockery and the bustling of dinner activity is loud enough to almost 
        drown out attempts at conversation. As your eyes adjust to the dimness, you see a burly 
        bartender filling mugs from behind a solid oak bar along the north wall.
        The bartender sees you and approaches. 
        The patrons notice you, and suddenly it becomes much quieter. 
    </intro>
	<room name="Main Room">
		The common room of this Inn in heated by the large fireplace 
	    near the center of the room. Rough wooden tables are scattered 
	    about the main floor. A couple of booths can be seen along the 
	    east wall. The aroma of roasted meats and ale is in the air, 
	    and the smokey smell of the fireplace. 
	</room>
	<people>
		<innkeeper name="Bork">
			<description type="far">
				The Innkeeper intently polishes glasses, but he notices every move in the Inn.	
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				The Innkeeper is a burly man with a thick beard. His apron is stained with food and 
				wine. The faint smell of fireplace smoke drifts to you as he gets closer.
		    	"See anything you like?", he asks in a semi-toothless smile.
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1"> 
				My name is Bork, and I own this fine establishment </message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2"> My Inn has great food, beer, wine, and a place to rest
				your feet after a weary day. Then he winks and says, "It also has some very 
				interesting characters here, if you know what I mean." 	</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="3">Buying drinks for folks will help loosen their tongues.</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="4">Don't insult someone before asking for a favor.</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="5">Make sure to have plenty of torches before going underground.</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1"> I'm the Innkeeper here. Wha'cha want?" </message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2"> What! </message>
			<message type="negative" rank="3">People who buy nothing make poor customers.</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="4">Are you going to buy something or just stand around looking pretty?</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="5">I'm busy right now. Talk to me in the morning.</message>
		</innkeeper>

		<patron name="Sal">
			<description type="far">
				A tiny man, wearing stained clothes, carries a huge burlap sack
				bulging with "something".
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				This tiny man is perpetually hunched over from his large 
				sack of shoes. Looking at your feet he smiles at you pathetically.
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1">"Sal's the name, cobbling is the game!"</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2">"Looks like you could use some good shoe leather."</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="3">"Rats make for lousy shoes."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1">"I peddle shoes not prattle! Beat it!"</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2">"No shoes, no service!"</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="3">"Not all the heels of this world are on shoes."</message>
		</patron>

		<patron name="Scruffy">
			<description type="far">
				A scruffy-looking old man with a grizzled chin looks around warily.
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				Close up, this old geezer is a mess. His hair is umcombed, his beard is gnarled,
				several teeth are missing, and he smells as if he hasn't had a bath since spring.	
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1">"Sit down and talk a spell."</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2">"You must be thirsty with all that curiosity built up, eh?"</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="3">"The mad hermit is alive and roams the northern forest."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1">"Go bother someone else."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2">"I don't know nuttin', and I don't want to talk about it."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="3">"Innkeeper! Can't a guy enjoy a little peace and quiet!"</message>
		</patron>

		<patron name="Boren">
			<description type="far">
				A large man sits astride his bench, sipping deeply on a stein of ale.
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				Although his face is ruddy and clean, his leather overalls are covered with soot 
				and coaldust. His forearms are as large as your thighs.
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1">He exhales alcoholic fumes in satisfaction.
				"Well stranger, sit down and whet your whistle."</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2">"I'm too thirsty to do much talking. You buying?"</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1">He stares at you silently.</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2">He furls his brow. "Hey buddy! I just came for a cool one, 
				not a conversation."</message>
			<message>RUMOR</message>
			<message>RETORT</message>
		</patron>

		<patron name="Meladriel">
			<description type="far">
				A beautiful young lady, in a low-cut purple dress, eyes you expectantly and smiles.  
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				The young lady stares alluringly into your eyes. "See anything you like?"
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1">"Hello," she says in a cool voice, "My name is Meladriel."</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2">I'm sure there is something I can do for you."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1">"You don't look like my type." </message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2">She puts on her cloak and covers her face.</message>
			<message>RUMOR</message>
			<message>RETORT</message>
		</patron>
 
		<patron name="Aragon">
			<description type="far">
				Obviously well-to-do, a gentleman in chainmail armor is busy eating a large dinner. 
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				As you approach, you see a barrel-chested man eating dinner. He shakes his head
				and smiles grimly to himself, as if to say, "Here comes another one."
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1">He smiles slightly and extends his hand, 
				offering a seat at his table.</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2"> "I'm always up for a good adventure myself."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1">He looks sideways at you and says, "Begone!"</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2">He puts his hand silently on the hilt of his sword, 
				and slowly rises.</message>
			<message>RUMOR</message>
			<message>RETORT</message>
		</patron>

		<patron name="Matilda">
			<description type="far">
				A plump woman in dusty traveling clothes eats noisily and alone at a table.
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				She continues to look at you and tears into a cooked chicken noisily, spattering little bits of food 
				on the table.
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1">Have a seat, and grab a leg if you want.</message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2"> "I like a man with a healthy appetite."</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1"> She continues to look at you and chews noisily, 
				spattering little bits of what looks like chicken on the table.</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2"> "Don't know nothing, and I'm busy."
				She pushes more food into her face so that she can't talk.</message>
			<message>RUMOR</message>
			<message>RETORT</message>
		</patron>

		<patron name="Perrin">
			<description type="far">
				A barrel-chested man, with a bow and quiver at his side, chews slowly and eyes you 
				from a distance. 
			</description>
			<description type="near">
				This man seems to have traveled many miles, but his worn pack, placed carefully 
				on the floor, is well-kept. He has an attitude of competence.
				He looks down at his food as you approach. 
			</description>
			<message type="positive" rank="1"> "Perrin's the name. I'm the village fletcher. He extends a calloused hand." </message>
			<message type="positive" rank="2">"If you've a need of anything, my shop is down the street. Can't miss it. I'll give you a good price." </message>
			<message type="negative" rank="1">He turns his back and continues eating.</message>
			<message type="negative" rank="2">"We don't cotton to strangers in this town. 
				It's a peaceful town, and we like it that way." </message>
			<message>RUMOR</message>
			<message>RETORT</message>
		</patron>
	</people>
</dungeon>
