<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<help_groups maxEntries='7' >
	<helptext helpID="MenuHelp">
	|CookieJar Help Window| Processing Help the first time....one moment, please.
	~~
	All options are available, given the correct program state, through the File and Help menus,
	even if they are not always available by the buttons.
	~~File->Add: Add your own fortune to the CookieJar for later retrieval. 
	~~File->Edit: Revise the text of an existing fortune.
	~~File->Delete: Permanently remove a fortune from the CookieJar
	~~File->Save: Save an edited or new fortune into the CookieJar.
	~~File->Exit: Quit the program. This is the same as clicking on the end-program icon in the
	top left corner of the window. 
	~~Help->Help: Get generic help about this program. If you hit the F1 key, specific help
	is displayed about the field or button currently in focus.
	~~Help->About: Displays the copyright, version, and credits for this program.
	</helptext>
	<helptext helpID="DgnName">
	|Dungeon Name| Enter the name of the dungeon. Hit the Enter key in this text field to copy
	the name to the window title. The name of the dungeon will be the default file name into
	which the data will be saved.  
	~~
	In the Player version of the game: The full name of the dungeon will become the window 
	title. 
	</helptext>
	<helptext helpID="Desc">
	|Dungeon Description| Enter a short description or summary statement about the dungeon.
	The text will scroll as needed. 
	~~
	In the Player version of the game: The description will be displayed as is. 
	</helptext>
	<helptext helpID="Story">
	|Background Story| Enter a background story about the dungeon. How did it come to exist?
	Why is there an opportunity for the Hero (player) to achieve fame or glory or treasure? 
	This is the story that 	motivates the player to enter the dungeon and play the game.
	~~
	In the Player version of the game: The background story is displayed automatically once 
	when the game starts up, and then only by request thereafter. 
	</helptext>
	<helptext helpID="SaveAs">
	|Save As Button| Trigger this button to save the dungeon to a new file name. 
	This button is active only 	when a New dungeon is being created. After the dungeon is 
	saved once to a file, it changes to a Save button from a SaveAs button. The Save As feature
	is still available from the File menu if the author wants to make a copy of an existing dungeon.
	~~
	In the Player version of the game: The filename is required to start the game, and updates 
	are saved to that file as the Player explores the dungeon.
	</helptext>
	<helptext helpID="Save">
	|Save Button| Trigger this button to save dungeon updates to its original file. 
	This button is active only if changes have been made to the dungeon attributes. 
	The Save feature is always available from the File menu.
	~~
	In the Player version of the game: The filename is required to start the game, and updates 
	are saved to it as the Player explores the dungeon.
	</helptext>
	<helptext helpID="Image">
	|Get Image Button| Trigger this button to read an image file and display it. 
	The image is best displayed, and in the quickest amount of time, if it is already about the
	same size of the image panel on the right side of the screen. 
	The aspect ratio should be 0.8 for best viewing because the image will be stretched to fit
	the panel. 
	Currently, only JPG images files are supported.
	~~
	In the Player version of the game: The image will be displayed when the game starts up,
	and will stay visible until the Player enter the dungeon's first room, or the Rumor Mill. 
	</helptext>
</help_groups>


